Good morning, everyone. Whoo! Good morning.
各位早上好。 Whoo! 早上好。
Welcome to React Conf 2018. My name is
欢迎来到 React Conf 2018。 我叫
Tom Occhino. I'm the engineering director
Tom Occhino。 我是 Facebook React 小组的
of the React Group at Facebook. I'm
技术总监。 真的非常
really excited to be here. I'm actually
激动来到这里。 我实际上真的
really excited to talk to people from
非常激动能够和
all over the country and actually all
全国的人，乃至全世界的人
over the world. And I know joining us on
对话。而且我知道
the live stream, we have people from all
还有在观看网络直播的各位, 我们拥有来自
over the place. So thank you for being
世界各地的观众。 非常感谢你们的
here with us. Before we get started just
到来。在开始之前，请允许我讲一些
a couple of quick logistics. If you
简单的后勤安排。 如果你
haven't read the Code of Conduct yet,
还没有阅读大会的行为规范，
please do so. It's posted by registration.
请阅读一下。 行为准则发布在了登记处，
It's posted on the website. Follow it. If
和我们大会的网站上。请准守行为准则。 如果
you have any issues, please reach out to
你有任何问题，请举手示意我
me or anyone on the staff. The staff is
或任何工作人员。 工作人员
all wearing purple shirts. Uh, we got a great
全部穿着紫色衬衫。 我们的演讲
lineup of talks. They're gonna be in this
阵容非常强大。在这里今明
room today and tomorrow. But if you need
两天会为你带来精彩的演讲。但如果你需要
anything else if, uh, if you need to just get
其他，呃， 如果你需要
away, if you need to make a phone call, we
离开，如果你需要接打电话，请到
have room set up actually directly
我身后的
behind me. The breakfast room is
房间。早餐厅
available. And in the hallway here, we're
已经开放了。在走廊里，可以看到
gonna have the fiber arts circle
Jen Lucas 的纤维艺术
knitting track with Jen Lucas, so check
圆形针织物展览, 有时间
that out as well. If you want to get away
可以去看看。如果你想离开。
from the talks. Uh, lastly there's gonna be, uh,
呃，今天会有
more updates throughout the day, we'll
更多的内容, 我们会在中午
have lunch at noon. But before the rest
进行午餐。 在演讲开始
of the the talks here, I just wanted to
之前, 我想
give a big thank you to the organizers. Uh,
对大会的组织者表示衷心的感谢。
putting this on is a lot of work. We were
组织这场大会的工作量非常大。我们之前有点担心
a little worried that we weren't gonna
我们今年可能没有办法
be able to put it on this year because
完成这项工作，因为
it is so much work. But we found the
工作量实在是太大了。 但是我们的大会
organizers of React Rally, ng-conf
组织者：React Rally, ng-conf
Jamieson, uh, Matt and and Joe and then Zero
Jamieson, Matt, Joe 还有 Zero
Slope Events really helped us get this, uh,
Slope Events 帮助我们
put together this year. And I'm really
完成了今年大会的筹备。 我真的
really happy that we were able to do it.
非常开心我们做到了。
Thank you all for being here. The first
非常感谢你们的到来。 第一个
talk is is our keynote talk with Sophie
演讲是我们的主题演讲，演讲者是 Sophie
Alpert and Dan Abramov. Uh, we're all really
Alpert 和 Dan Abramov。 我们真的
looking forward to this. I'm gonna invite
非常期待。 下面允许我有请
Sophie up first to kick things off for
Sophie 给我们带来开场演讲，
us, thanks.
谢谢。
[Applause]
[掌声]
Good morning. see ... ya ... there ... Uh, hello everyone,
早上好。大家好，
welcome to React Conf. I'm really excited
欢迎来到 React 大会。今天来到这里我感到
to be here. I'm really excited for the
非常激动。我非常激动
stuff that we have to announce, uh, for you
本周可以给你们
this week. Um, my name is Sophie Alpert at
做开场演讲。我是 Sophie Alpert，个人主页是
sophiebits on the Internet.
sophiebits。
I manage the React core team at Facebook.
我是 Facebook React 核心小组的经理。
By any better that you use React is
你们正在使用的 React
doing great.
做的很好。
Our npm downloads are up 70%
我们在 npm 的下载量一年内增加了
year-over-year. The Chrome Dev Tools
70 %。 React Dev Tools 在 Chrome 开发者工具
extension for React Dev Tools has been
扩展程序的安装量
installed by one and a quarter million
达到了 125 万。
developers. And I can show you this list
这是使用 React 的
of companies that's using React. Although
公司列表。此时此刻，
at this point, it's so long, it's kind of
这个列表已经非常长了，我们很难
hard to tell how much it changes each
说清每年使用 React 的公司的变化。
year. For another point of data, we can
我们来看另一组数据，我们来看看
look at Google Trends, which shows web
Google 趋势, 它可以反映出网络搜索的
search traffic. So it searches for React
流量。可以看到，React 的搜索量
continue to go up. Hopefully that means
一直在增加。 希望这个数据表示
more people are using React not that
有更多的人在使用 React，而不是
it's getting more confusing. [Laughing] Um, but, uh, for a
React 变得更加令人困惑了。 [笑声] 嗯，为了
point of comparison, we can look at, um,
做比较，我们比较了 jQuery 的
jQuery which we have just passed for the
搜索量，我们的搜索量刚刚在历史上首次
first time in history. [Cheer & Applause]
超越了 jQuery。[欢呼和掌声]
But this also shows that we have a lot
但这也表明，我们仍然有很多
more room to grow. Um, I was procrastinating
成长的空间。呃，我在写这个演讲时
when I was writing this talk. So I was
被耽搁了一会儿。 因为我比较
curious to see what else React is more
好奇 React 还比什么更
popular than. Oops. [Laughing]
流行。 哎呀。 [笑声]
Spoiled my joke. Um, but React is more
当我开了个玩笑。嗯，我发现 React
popular ,I found out, than renewable
比可再生能源
energy. [Laughing] It's also more popular than
更流行。 [笑声] React 也比
orange juice. [Laughing] Just think about how common
橙汁更流行。 [笑声] 想想橙汁是多么
orange juice is ,right. And not only that
常用啊，是吧。而且 React 比
it's more popular than renewable energy
可再生能源和橙汁加在一起
and orange juice put together. So I think
更流行。所以我认为
we have a lot to be proud of. But, um, but
我们有理由感到非常自豪。 但是
enough about these numbers, uh, what I really
除了这些数字，我今天真正想要讲的
like to talk about today is our mission
是 React 的
with React.
使命。
Um, ever since React was released in 2013,
呃，自从 2013 年 React 发布以来，
our overarching goal,
我们首要的目标、
our primary mission has been to make it
主要的使命就是：让开发者更容易地构建
easier to build great UIs. And so when
好的 UI。所以当我们
we're adding new features, we always try
想要增加新的特性时，我们通常都是
to be very deliberate. We want to
要经过深思熟虑。当我们决定是否增加新的 API 时，
consider a bunch of things when deciding
我们需要考虑非常多的事情。
whether to add a new API. If it makes it
如果增加新的 API 能够
possible to do something you couldn't do
让你做到一些以前做不到的事情；
before. If it can dramatically simplify
如果可以显著简化
the code around React in your components
组件里的代码
and libraries so that you all have less
和类库，让你的工作量
work to do and users have less code to
减小，用户下载更少的代码，
download, that's a win. Or if it helps
那新增 API 就是有价值的。或者如果新增 API 能够帮助
encourage best practices like code
我们做到代码分割的
splitting,  if we make it easier to code
最佳实践，如果能够更容易地将你 app 里面的代码
split your app into multiple bundles,
分割成多个包，
then our hope is that your apps will end
我们希望你的 app 最终可以
up being faster. So that's why we add
运行更快。这也是我们两周之前
things like React.lazy which we
宣布增加像 React.lazy 这样的
announced two days ago. You might have
API 的原因。 你们可能已经
seen it. But thinking about this mission,
注意到了这个 API。 但想想 React 的使命，
make it easier to great ... to build great
让开发者更容易地构建好的
UIs.
UI。
There are a lot of different ways that
我们有很多方法来
we approach this. One way we do this is
实现这个目标。 其中一点是
trying to simplify things that are hard.
我们尝试简化复杂的东西。
If you saw Dan Abramov's talk from
如果你看了 Dan Abramov 在冰岛的
JS Conf Iceland, then you saw a sneak
JS Conf 上的演讲，你可以抢先
peek at "Suspense",  which is our idea about
看到 "Suspense",  "Suspense" 是我们
how to dramatically simplify what's
用来显著简化
required to do data fetching, code
获取数据请求、代码分割
splitting and any kind of async data
和异步数据
dependencies in your app. Now another way
依赖的问题。 另外一个我们尝试
we try to improve React is by focusing
去提升 React 的方式
on performance. If your app runs faster,
就是提升性能。如果你的 app 运行速度更快，
your users are going to enjoy using it
你的用户就会更原意使用它。
more. Conversely, if your
相反的，如果你的
app is laggy, if your app is junky,  then
app 反映很慢，速度卡顿，那
there your users aren't gonna have a
你的用户肯定不会有很好的
great time. So we try to spend time on
体验。因此我们尝试让
making React itself faster, because if
React 本身运行的更快，如果
React is faster out of the box, you all
React 开箱就很快，那么你们
need to spend less time optimizing your
就会省下很多优化你自己代码的时间。
own code. One recent performance related
最近和提升性能有关的内容，
effort that Dan also talked about in
Dan 也在冰岛的 JS Conf 上
Iceland, as what we call "Time Slicing".
提到了，我们称其为 "Time Slicing"。
Uh, this is going to let you make sure that
"Time Slicing" 可以确保
the most important renders in your app
你 app 里面最重要的渲染
are processed first, in order to unblock
会最先执行，解除主线程的
the main thread and make your apps
阻塞，并且能让你的 app 运行地
faster. And a third angle that we
更快速。 第三种方式是
approach our mission from is Developer
使用开发者工具
tooling to help you debug and understand
帮助你 debug ，进而更了解
your app. From the start,
你的 app。一开始，
React has included developer friendly
React 就包含了对开发者友好的
warnings to help, uh, point out problems
警告来帮助开发者指出问题，
before you might otherwise notice them.
以防开发者没有注意到这些问题。
And we've had the React Dev Tools
而且我们的 React Dev Tools
extension which lets you inspect and
扩展程序能够让你检查并且
debug your component trees. And in React
debug 你的组件树。 在 React
16.5, we introduced a new Profiler. It's a
16.5 版本，我们引入了一个叫 Profiler 的新特性。它是
second ... (I don't know what's up with this
第二个 ... （我不知道这个遥控器出了什么问题
clicker)... A second tab their, profiler tab
）... 图上的第二个标签栏就是 profiler 标签栏，
that helps you understand what's
它能够帮助我们了解到
happening in your app and optimize it. So
你 app 中到底发生了什么，然后更好地优化它。所以
Suspense, Time Slicing and the Profiler
Suspense, Time Slicing 和 Profiler
are three of the new features that we've
这三个新特性是我们
been working on over the last year. We're
去年一直在做的事情。 我们
really excited to tell you more about
真的想多说一些关于这三个特性的
them. But that's actually not what I'm
内容。但是这些并不是我今天在这里想要
here to talk about. You're gonna have to
讲的。大家可以等到明天，
wait till Andrew and Brian's talk
Andrew 和 Brian 会在明天早上
tomorrow morning to hear about that.
给大家带来关于这个内容的演讲。
Today I want to take a step back and
现在我想退一步，
focus on something else.
我们来关注一些其他的问题。
What I like to ask is what in React
我想问的是，现在 React 还有什么
still sucks. And I have three problems
糟糕的地方。我总结出了三个问题，
that I would like to talk through. The
在这里想和大家来讨论。
first one is reusing logic between
第一个问题就是多组件间的逻辑复用
multiple components. In React our main
问题。在 React 中我们主要使用
building block for our applications is a
组件来构建我们的应用，
component, and components form the
组件主要有
foundation of the two main patterns for
两种主要的模式
sharing code in React apps between
来复用代码：
components which are Higher-order
它们是高阶组件（higher-order）
components and Render props. Both of
和渲染属性（render props)。这两种
these patterns are great for some cases,
模式对于某些场景来说是很好的，
but they also come with a significant
但是它们也造成了一个极大的
downside. You need to restructure your
缺点。在更加复杂的场景中，
app anytime you want to pull one of
你必须将他们抽离出来去
these in in more complicated examples.
重构你的 app。
This leads to what I call wrapper hell.
这会导致一个问题，我称之为”包装地狱“（wrapper hell）。
Uh, most of us have seen component trees
嗯，我们经常会看到
that look something like this. [Screaming & Laughing]
像这样的组件树。 [尖叫和笑声]
And the the nesting you end up with
而且这种嵌套会造成
makes it difficult to follow the data
跟踪 app 数据流的困难。
flow through the app. It would be really
如果
nice if there was some way to reuse this
能够复用这类
sort of stateful logic without needing
有状态的逻辑，而不需要
to change the component hierarchy, right.
修改组件的层级，那肯定是很好的方法，对吧。
The second problem I would like to talk
第二个我像讲的问题是
about is giant components whose logic is
庞大的组件，它的逻辑
just sort of a tangled mess. When you
杂乱无章。 我们来看看一个
look at a thousand line React component
上千行代码的 React 组件，
chances are the logic is going to be
我们会发现逻辑
split across a lot of different
分散到了许多不同的
lifecycle methods in a way that's pretty
生命周期函数中，这样
difficult to follow. Let's look at an
非常难以跟踪。我们来看一个
example. Let's say we have a class
例子。这里有一个 class
component, and in its component did mount
组件，在它的 did mount
method it does a few different things: it
方法，它做了几件事：它
subscribes to a datastore, it sends off a
订阅了一个数据存储中，然后发送了一个
network requests and it starts a timer.
网络请求，最后开启了一个定时器。
Well, if we look at the component will
那么，如果我们来看组件的 will
unmount method, then we're going to see
unmount 方法，我们会看到
basically the exact three opposite
基本完全相反的
things: it needs to unsubscribe from the
代码：首先需要取消存储的订阅，
store, it needs to cancel that network
然后取消网络请求，
request and it needs to stop the timers.
最后停止定时器。
And when it comes to implementing
当我们要实现
component did update, the logic tends to
组件的 did update 方法, 里面的逻辑会
get even trickier because you need to
更加的 tricky。因为你需要
compare the old and new props and (ur, and
比较新旧的属性
and) also mirror it again the same tasks
然后再一次重复和其他生命周期函数内部
that you have in your other lifecycle
相同的任务逻辑。
methods. Uh, in this example, each call here
呃，在这个例子里，每个请求都是
is just one line so this is actually a
只有一行，所以说这个例子实际上比
lot simpler than what you normally see
你平时看到的组件要
in your components. In real-world
简单的多。在真实组件中，
components you often end up with an even
逻辑往往会更加错综复杂，
more tangled mess, because each (ur, each)
因为每个
individual task has to be split across
独立的任务分散到了
different lifecycle methods, that makes
不同的生命周期函数中，这样
it hard to tell if, for instance, you
会造成困难，举个例子，当你 unmounting 组件时，
forgot to clean up one of the resources
你可能会
when you're unmounting your component.
忘记清除资源。
It's pretty hard to see that from the
这非常难以从代码中找到
code. And the third thing that sucks is
问题。 第三个糟糕的事情是
the class, ur, understanding classes in
class。理解 JavaScript 里的 classes
JavaScript can be pretty tricky, and
会相当 tricky，而且现在
today we require you to use class
我们要求你们使用 class 组件，
components in order to access state and
为了能够使用 state 和
lifecycles. If you've ever taken a
生命周期。如果你用过
function component and converted it to a
function 组件，而且将其转为了
class to add some state, you know that
class 组件，增加了一些 state，你就会知道
there's a fair amount of boilerplate
需要有大量的样本文件
that's required in order to just define
作用仅仅是用来定义一个
a class component. Most beginners and
class 组件。大多数初学者和
many experienced devs also tell us that
很多有经验的开发者也都跟我们抱怨过
the way binding and this work in classes
在 class 里面的绑定和转化工作
is pretty confusing. It's annoying to
相当令人困惑。 我们有必要来
have to think about. And we also
考虑这个问题。而且我们经常听说
frequently hear that people don't
大家并不是
exactly
非常清楚
know when to use function components
什么时候使用 function 组件，
partly because there's always this fear
一部分原因是他们总会担心
that you're gonna have to convert it to
早晚需要将这个组件转化为
a class later anyway. And so you're like
class 组件。所以你们可能会困惑，
should I ,should I do it now? I don't know.
我现在是否应该这么做？我不知道。
And so I claim classes are hard for
所以我说 classes 对于人类来说
humans,  uh, but it's not just humans,  I claim
是很难的，但是不是对于人类而言是这样，我也断言
the classes are also hard for machines.
classes 对于机器而言也是很难的。
If you ever looked at a minified
如果你看过压缩后的
component file, you'll see that all the
组件文件，可以看到所有的
method names are still unminified. And that if
方法名没有被压缩。而且如果
you have a method that's completely
你有一个完全没有使用的方法，
unused, it doesn't get stripped out.
它也没有被剔除出去。
That's because it's hard to tell at
这是因为在编译时
compile time
很难准确判断
exactly how all the methods fit together.
方法是否被使用。
We also found that classes make it
我们还发现 classes 使得
difficult for us to implement hot
可靠的热加载变得困难。
reloading reliably. And finally when we
最后当我们
were prototyping an optimizing compiler
设计一个优化的编译器原型来
to improve the performance of React
提升 React 组件性能时，
components, we found that classes can
我们发现 class 组件
encourage some patterns that make it a
的一些模式使得
lot harder for compilers to optimize.  So
编译器优化变得更难。所以，
here are the three problems that we have:
我们现在有三个问题：
reusing logic, giant components, and (ur, and)
逻辑复用、庞大的组件和
classes. So reusing logic because you
classes。逻辑复用的问题会导致你
often end up with this wrapper hell.
经常遇到“包装地狱“。
Giant components because you have the
庞大组件的原因是由于
logic split across different lifecycles.
逻辑分散到了不同的生命周期中。
And classes which are difficult for both
而令人困惑的 classes 无论对于人类还是机器来说
humans and machines. So we think we have
都是个难题。 我们认为我们有了一个
a solution that can help with all three
能够解决以上三个问题的解决方案。
of these. We're really excited to share
我们特别像把这个方案分享给大家。
it with you to tell you more about it. I
请允许我请出
want to welcome up Dan Abramov.
Dan Abramov 为我们带来接下来的演讲。
[Applause]
[掌声]